this video is going to show you how to
organize your GitHub repos and why you
might want to do that and I'm going to
go ahead and I've got a container that
I'm already building on that I need to
do this for then I'm also going to show
you how to quickly configure a new
account so that you can use all your
favorite things so here we have uh a
Docker repo that I have create um so I'm
on I'm on t-x I'm running in a VM uh I'm
on a system and I have Docker running
over here and I'm going to go ahead and
I'm going to hey how you doing B we're
going to do Docker exec it amazing mu
bash we're going to run bash on this
this container that's been set up and
had the stuff in it it puts me in his
root and then I've already created a new
account over here so I'm going to go to
that account rvx Rob uh d uh GH test 3
and as you can see there's no
configuration here there's nothing here
at all and you're like well how do I
what's the quickest way to stand up you
know it's a tech term um my environment
here right so I can do this pretty
quickly by first of all creating a
similar directory structure to that the
one that I have used before so the way
you do that is I make a directory called
repos you could do lowercase for many
years I did uh the repos is just left
over from when I used to use graphic
desktop Linux um and it's built into my
Bach RC now so uh it's still uppercase
next we make uh GitHub directory because
we organize our cont content in our
repos based on the domain that you're on
and I want to emphasize this it's very
important to do this because then you
don't have problems with conflicts with
your git repos uh you may have two
things that want to have the same space
so that's why we do that next we go into
the GitHub rep the the first one and
inside of here we're going to make
another directory I'm going to name it
um in this case I'm going to make RBX
Rob uh because for reasons I get to in a
minute and then I'm going to CD into RDX
Robin here so you can see our path there
repos github.com RBX Rob now from inside
of here I don't have I have the GitHub
tool installed so I can do a get a get
clone but a lot of times you're not
going to have the GitHub tool installed
so you're just going to have to use git
so you can do a get clone and you can do
you don't even have to have an
authenticated access you can do the
non-authenticated htps uh to get the
repo and I'm going to download my DOT
files
so there they come and this is a readon
copy of the directory if I were to go in
here and to change it um you know if I
were to try to attempt to change
something uh you know uh change and if I
were to do you know a get uh uh commit
Dash a wait get
commit whoopsie commit um it doesn't
have completion or anything so I'm kind
of hating it uh
changed uh you know I have to do all the
other setup and everything but even if I
had that setup I'm not going to bother
with that right now if I did it get push
it would fail right because it's a read
only it doesn't have access to it itd
have to have other access to it but it's
okay it's good enough it's good enough
for now because if you look at my setup
directory which we are not going to go
through I have created Sim links which
is a pretty standard way to do this uh
to all of my files so that they're all
here um I've seen people make videos
complaining about the use of sim links
for this kind of thing and I still find
it to be the easiest and clearest and
and something that I have the best
control of there's a bunch of tools that
attempt to do what you want to do
nothing is better than your own script A
lot of times seriously this is why you
should learn how to script because then
you can make your own modifications and
manage your own dot files as you want to
you're not going to be you know uh
constantly shoehorning a tool that
somebody else made to do what you want
so this is one of those cases where I
would make a strong argument that dot
files I'll do a separate video on do
files but this is one of those cases
where I I do really believe that you
should take the time to create your own
most popular system for this kind of
stuff so then I run the setup
tool and we get a bunch of stuff okay
and it didn't show up um and it's s
saying here you should probably
authenticate with GitHub blah blah blah
we're going to do that we're going to
get to this step right here in a second
but but you know Mr Rob what happened I
don't see anything here right Rob
nothing nothing's happening well that's
because you need to start up your new
shell don't log out of the terminal and
log back in that's stupid just do exac
b-l it's because you want to login shell
and the exec if you don't know what exec
is if you don't if you haven't heard of
exec before exec replaces the currently
running process with the process that
you are going to kick off so all of its
resources get taken over by it this is
very very very critical it's very
important so that means any open pipes
any any um the environment the variables
are adopted in um it basically it
replaces the currently running I've said
it already so you really want to get
good with doing this because this is the
fastest way for you to reinitialize uh a
shell using the thing that there's so
many people who don't know to do that I
should probably just do a video about
that um so so there we go now we see
we've got you know my favorite little
you know prompt here which by the way
does get smaller if the The Prompt is a
little bit it it does not always on two
lines it only does that if it's above
like 30 characters or so if you want to
understand where that is coming from you
can go look at the at the PS um stuff
inside of my bash RC but that's not this
video this video is just how did I how
do I get an account set up and I'm done
I'm done my friends I'm done I now have
everything I cared about already set up
in fact I still even have fishies here
I'm pretty sure yep there's my fishes so
this has been a very quick video about
the method of of creating um very
quickly an account based on your single
original account using ad dot files
inside of a Docker container or anywhere
it could have been a VM or anything I am
that close to being up and running uh by
just those few steps and it took us a
few minutes I want to keep this video
short so I'll stop there and we'll do I
mean from here I can go ahead and set up
the credentials for this like as I would
in any other system to contact it or you
know whatever it is that I'm need to set
up uh access
to bye